A Guide to the Papers of Homer Stille Cummings, ca.1850-1955
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
- SERIES III: CORRESPONDENCE OF THE ATTORNEY GENERAL AND POST-ATTORNEY GENERAL, 1933-1956
  - Attorney General Personal File - J.R. Carroll 1935 January-1951 October (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Ugo Carusi 1939 March-1947 August (Box 85)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Theron Lamar Caudle, Assistant Attorney general (dismissed by President Truman) 1949 December-1955 January (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Nathan Cayton, D.C. Judge 1936 July-1939 August (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Thomas L. Chadbourne 1935 May-1938 June (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Hammond E. Chaffitz 1938 January-1942 April (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - "Chalice of Antioch" (Fahim Kouchakji) 1933 September-1937 March (Box 85)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Chamber of Commerce of U.S. 1937 January (Box 85)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Child Labor Amendment 1935 February (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Chillicothe Prison, Ohio, Allegations of Prison Brutality 1936 July-August (Box 85)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - "Chronicles of America" 1950 (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William Citron, Congressman from Connecticut 1936 March-1940 May (Box 85)
  - Civil Service, Executive Order #7916 as it effects Department of Justice 1938 December (Box 85)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Brice Claggett 1953 September-1942 June (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Raymond Clapper, D.C. journalist (Box 85)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Charles E. Clark, Dean of Yale Law School 1933 October-1954 January (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Tom C. Clark, Assistant Attorney General 1943 March-1956 February (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William Clark, Judge from New York 1936 December-1938 (Box 86)
  - Papers re: proposed D.C. Clinic 1949 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence with Ralph Close 1943 December-1944 January (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John J. Cochran, Congressman from Missouri 1936 July-1936 November (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James L. Coke, Chief Justice of Supreme Court of Hawaii 1934 October-1938 October (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Bainbridge Colby 1934 March-1935 February (Box 86)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Paolo E. Coletta 1955 June-1956 (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Linton M. Collins 1935 March-1956 May (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William T. Collins 1933 June-1945 March (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Columbia Legation 1936 (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Columbia Gas Company 1935 March-1938 November (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William H. Comley 1937 April-1939 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Commission on Judicial and Congressional Salaries 1953 December-1954 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Committee on Construction of New Court House 1940 (Box 86)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Community War Fund & Chest Trophy 1944 October (Box 86)
  - Correspondence and Memoranda of Homer Stille Cummings re: Comptroller General 1933 July-1937 February (Box 86)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Martin Conboy 1934 April-1936 December (Box 87)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Letters of Condolence 1933-1938 (Box 87)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Congratulatory letters received by Homer Stille Cummings (many rlating to Democratic successes in the 1936 campaign) 1934 March-1936 November (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Congratulatory messages sent by Attorney General (large number of items for 1934 election) (Box 87)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Clara B. & Homer Congdon (related to Homer Stille Cummings) 1952 September (Box 87)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Tom Connally, Senator from Texas 1935 February-September (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut Libraries 1939 October-1942 October (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut Shipbuilding Association 1939 January (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut State Bar Association 1950 March-1956 May (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut Presidential Electors 1944 1944 November-December (Box 87)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Connecticut State Convention matters (including material on the Connecticut delegation to the National Convention) 1936 April-June (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut State Convention, June 3-4, 1940 1940 May-June (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut State Convention, August 1940 1940 August (Box 87)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Connecticut Democratic State Convention 1942 September (Box 87)
  - Miscellaneous Political Papers, including lists of delegates, resulting from the Connecticut State Convention, Hartford, Connecticut 1944 August 4-5 (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Mrs. Elizabeth Marney Conner 1928 October-1941 April (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Paul R. Connery 1935 July-1946 August (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Constitution, pledge in support of n.d. (Box 88)
  - Memoranda, articles, and clipings re: Constitutional Questions 1935 June-1938 October, 2 folders (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Memoranda re: Constitutionality of Statutes 1936 January-February (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Continuous Discharge Books 1936 December (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Control of prices in event of war 1938 September (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Courtney Riley Cooper, author 1936 January-1940 July (Box 88)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings with Hugh Cope 1933 October 2 (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Robert A. Cooper, Judge in Puerto Rico 1938 October-December (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Royl S. Copeland, Senator from New York 1935 March-1938 June (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Thomas G. Cororan, Reconstruction Finance Corporation 1936 September-1938 October (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward S. Corwin, Professor of Politics at Princeton 1936 February-1937 October (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Court Building in D.C. 1938 July-September (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John R. Covert, Philadelphia journalist 1938 February-September (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Judge Pierre Crabites 1938 March-November (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Bennett Crain, Mails & Files Division, Department of Justice 1937 December-1956 July (Box 88)
  - Attorney General Personal File - George Creel, writer on staff of Collier's 1933 September-1938 October (Box 89)
  - W.B. Shelby Crichlow 1939 November (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John W.H. Crim 1933 April-July (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Crime Bills 1934 July (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - "Towards a More Effective Criminal Law" [1937 January] (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John C. Crosby, Postmaster, Huntington, Indiana 1933 May-1940 April (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Wilbur L. Cross, Governor of Connecticut 1932 November-1938 December (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James E. Cuff, re: Postmastership of Danbury, Connecticut 1933 March-1935 August (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Francis D. Culkin, Congressman from New York 1935 February-1937 November (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John T. Cullinen, Connecticut Judge 1934 July-1951 October (Box 89)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Hon. Homer S. Cummings 1933-1935, 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings re: William J. Curtin 1945 May-June (Box 89)
  - Personal Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Da-Di" 1934-1956, 2 folders (Box 89)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Dob-Dy" 1934-1950, 2 folders (Box 90)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Dairy Industry, Conspiracy in restraint of trade [1934] (Box 90)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Leigh Danenberg 1935 February-1940 (Box 90)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Elsie N. Danenberg 1933 December-1934 January (Box 90)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Josephus Daniels, Ambassador to Mexico 1933 March-1945 December (Box 90)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Joseph Edward Davies 1933 April-1954 April (Box 90)
    includes long Russian paper re: 1937 treason show trials in Russia
  - Attorney General Personal File - Chester C. Davis, Board of Governors, Federal Reserve System 1935 September-1942 June (Box 90)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Kenneth Dawson 1934 October-1944 April (Box 90)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - William E. Day 1941 December-1947 November (Box 91)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Claude M. Dean, U.S. District Court Clerk, Richmond, Virginia 1938 June-1953 July (Box 91)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Gordon Dean, Special Executive Assistant to the Attorney General, late head of the Atomic Energy Commission 1937-1954 (Box 91)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Deceased persons - condolences 1933-1941 (Box 91)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Donald Defrees, Chicago lawyer 1933 May-1956 July (Box 91)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Committee 1939 June-1943 November (Box 91)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Committee 1943 February-1956 July, 7 folders (Box 92)
  - Notes & Memoranda - Democratic National Convention and the Two Thirds Rule 1932 (Box 93)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Committee 1936 January-December, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Attorney General Personal File - 1936 Democratic National Convention, newspaper clippings & transcripts 1936 (Box 93)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Committee 1937 January-September & 1940 April, 2 folders (Box 93)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Convention, 1944 1944 May-July (Box 94)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Convention, 1948 1948 May-July (Box 94)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Campaign & Inaugural Matters 1948 August-1949 January (Box 94)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic National Committee 1952, including numerous newspaper clippings 1952 July-September (Box 94)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Central Committee of Connecticut 1940 September-1956 August (Box 94)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Convention, 1940, Hartford, Connecticut 1940 August (Box 95)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Convention, 1944 1944 May-August (Box 95)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Convention, Hartford, 1946 (Box 95)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Convention & Campaign 1948 May-December (Box 95)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic State Convention 1952 (Box 95)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Democratic Town Committee of Greenwich 1940 September-1954 October (Box 95)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William Denman, California Judge, 9th U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals 1936 December-1949 December (Box 95)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Departmental Survey (Personal Review) 1937 April-July (Box 95)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Department of Justice Building 1936 April (Box 96)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Department of Justice Correspondence Association n.d. (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - George W. Dern, Secretary of War 1936 April-1938 December (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John P. Devaney, Judge from Minnesota 1937 March-April (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Paul F. Dickens, D.C. Physician 1938 October-1955 July (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Dickinson, Assistant Attorney 1934 October-1952 November (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Dickinson's speech at Bedford, Pa., controversy it created 1936 August-September (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Bernard Dickman, Mayor of St. Louis 1935 December-1941 June (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William H. Dietrich, Senator from Illinois 1935 August-1940 October (Box 96)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Richard E. Dillon 1952 January-February (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Anthony J. Diamond, Congressman from Alaska 1937 February-December (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Captain James Dinkins 1933 November-1939 June (Box 96)
  - Papers of Homer Stille Cummings re: Disabled American Veterans 1948 (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - District of Columbia Police Form Investigations 1936 January-February (Box 96)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - District of Columbia Jail 1936 December-1937 January (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Dixie Terminal Company v. U.S. 1935 November-1937 November (Box 96)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Frederick C. Dockweiler 1943 March-1951 November (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Thomas J. Dodd, Congressman from Connecticut 1948 May-1956 July (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - William E. Dodd 1933 June-1937 May (Box 96)
  - Correspondence and Papers re: U.S. of America v. Doheny Executives: Application of Special Assistants Martineau and Lewison for additional compensation 1937 May 25-December 2 (Box 96)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward G. Dolan 1933 March-1940 January (Box 96)
  - "A Brief Day to day Account of trip to the Dominican Republic, February 3-20, 1946" by Homer Stille Cummings 1946 [February] (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Dominican Republic, chiefly with Generalissimo Trujillo and Ambassadors Troncaso & Thomen 1947 May-1955 May (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Dominican Republic's Embassy 1951 August-1954 September (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Vic Donahey 1936 December-137 January (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - John M. Donnelly 1934 September-December (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John E. Doughan, Sr. 1938 September-October (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Paul Douglas, Senator from Illinois 1954 November (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Eddie Dowling, New York Songwriter and Theatrical Producer 1933 September-1937 December (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Homer Cummings Downey 1936 December-1937 January (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Michael Francis Doyle 1948 (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Dravo Contracting Company (Tax Exemption cases) 1937 August (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Drivers' licenses and Registration Certificate 1930 (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Colonel Maurice Drummond, New Scotland Yard 1935 November-1936 July (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - F.W. Drybrough 1933 October-1934 October (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - David Dubinsky 1947 January (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - T. Howard Duckett 1935 August-1954 December (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - F. Ryan Duffy, Senator from Wisconsin 1935 August-1939 July (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Ward Duffy 1938 September (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Duke Power Company 1936 December-1937 August (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Woodson K. Duke 1936 September-December (Box 97)
  - Attorney General Personal File - John Foster Dulles 1939 April (Box 97)
  - Edward Dumbauld 1937 May-1955 March (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Jesse W.M. Dumond (primarily in relation to Dr. Pierre E. Marmier) 1947 March-1952 August (Box 97)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Louisa Dumond 1945 November-1956 June (Box 98)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Milton S. Durgy 1939 February-1952 September (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - E.P. Dutton & Do., Inc. 1935 July (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Rodney Dutcher 1937 July-1938 November (Box 98)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "E" (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Stephen Early1933 November-1952 February (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Stephen Early & David Lawrence 1937 June (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Sherwood Eddy 1936 October-1948 November (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Electric Bond & Share Company 1937 November-1938 September (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Henry W. Edgerton, Cornell Law School 1937 December-1951 June (Box 98)
  - Biographical Information & Articles re: Henry W. Edgerton 1937-[1940] (Box 98)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Complimentary letters re: editorials 1938 March-June (Box 98)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Arthur F. Egner, New Jersey lawyer 1934 October-1937 April (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J.C.B. Ehringhaus 1937 March-1938 February (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - re: Albert Einstein's citizenship 1934 (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Lewis Einstein, former Ambassador to Czechoslovakia 1930 October-1937 April (Box 99)
  - Election Prediction made by Homer Stille Cummings on 24 August 1944; Miscellaneous notes ca. 1944-1945 (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electors, Connecticut, Presidential Election 1940 November-December (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electoral Colleges Committee 1940 December-1942 July (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electoral Colleges Committee; 1945 Elector's Dinner 1944 December-1946 March (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electoral Colleges Committee, includes plans for a memorial plaque of Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1947-1948 1947 January-1948 November (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electoral Colleges Committee, 1949 Presidential Inauguration Dinner 1948 December-1949 June (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Electoral Colleges Committee 1953 (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Eligibility of German Alien for a Visa 1938 December 31 (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Eligibility of Congressman to Appointive Positions 1934 May-1935 July (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Arthur F. Ells, Connecticut Judge 1936 July-1946 June (Box 99)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Employees at West Palm Beach 1952-1955 (Box 99)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Enlisting in Foreign Service (Recruitment of forces in U.S. by Spanish loyalists in Civil War) 1938 February (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Espionage Committee 1938 October (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Esquire article 1934 May-1938 February (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - J.Fred Essary 1933 March-1942 April (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - W. Collier Estes 1935 May 1937 December (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Joe Garner Estill 1933 December-1938 September (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - 1935 European trip (investigating the prison and policy procedures of several countries) 1935 August-November (Box 100)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Everglades Club 1947-1955 (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Exportation of Arms to Germany 1938 July (Box 100)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - General "Fa-Fi" 1933-1956, 2 folders (Box 100)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Fair Campaign Practices Committee, Inc. 1954 September-1956 July (Box 101)
  - Homer Stille Cummings' letter of farewell to his friends and associates in the Department of Justice 1938 December 27 (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Judge Charles B. Faris 1934 October (Box 100)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - James A. Farley's and 1936 Campaign 1936 June-October (Box 101)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James A. Farley re: charges made by Senator Huey P. Long 1935 February-March (Box 100)
  - Attorney General Personal File - James A. Farley 1933 April-1938 February, 2 folders (Box 100)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - James A. Farley's book Why I Broke with Roosevelt 1947-1948 (Box 101)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - George R. Farnum, Boston lawyer and former Assistant Attorney General 1939 November-1942 October (Box 101)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Federal Bar Association 1939 May-1952 June (Box 101)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Criticism of the FBI by the Department of Justice Lodge, American Federation of Governmental Employees 1936 July-October (Box 102)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Federal Bar Association, re: Chairmanship of Legislative Committee 1943 April-1944 August, 2 folders (Box 102)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Criticism of FBI by National Probation Association, also letters of support in FBI 1936 June-August (Box 102)
  - Attorney General Personal File - FBI Retirement 1936 March-September (Box 102)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Federal Communications Commission, editorials and news releases 1943 August (Box 102)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Federal Incorporation 1936 February-1938 November (Box 102)
  - Correspondence & Papers of Homer Stille Cummings re: Federal Rules of Civil Procedure 1934 June-1938 December, 2 folders (Box 103)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Robert M. Field, Assistant Attorney General and Associate Administrator, War Assets Administration 1933 January-1956 February (Box 103)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward A. Filene 1935 December-1937 May (Box 103)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Firearms and National Firearms Act 1935 Man-1938 September (Box 103)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - First Presbyterian Church, Stamford, Connecticut 1943 January-1951 June (Box 104)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Irving Fisher, Emeritus Professor of Economics at Yale 1933 October-1944 August, 2 folders (Box 104)
  - Attorney General Personal File - David E. Fitzgerald 1933 March-1937 December (Box 104)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - James Lloyd Fisher 1948 September-October (Box 104)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - David E. Fitzgerald 1938 April-1942 December, 2 folders (Box 105)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - John Clark Fitzgerald 1949 January-1951 February (Box 105)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - "Colonel" Jay Fitzpatrick 1944 January-1956 May (Box 105)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Fletcher v. U.S. (Customs case) 1937 November (Box 105)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - James L. Fly 1938 January-1944 November (Box 105)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Edward J. Flynn, Secretary of State of New York 1935 October-1955 August (Box 105)
  - Correspondence of Homer Stille Cummings - Frank M. Folsom 1939 February-1940 November (Box 105)
  - Attorney General Personal File - Foreign Relations, Power of President in 1937 (Box 105)